Kenneth Kaijage

586 Falcon Ridge Rd Woodbury, MN 55125 ■ kennykaijage@gmail.com © (763)-742-2834 Kenny Kaijage Portfolio

SUMMARY

An experienced professional with a Bachelor's degree in Statistics and a minor in Economics with a passion of understanding data. Analytical, action oriented, and hardworking with a strong ability of utilizing critical thinking and teamwork to solve problems.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota-Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Statistics, Minor in Economics

September 2016 – May 2020

- Area of Emphasis; Statistical Practice.
- Relevant Coursework: Intro to C++; Theory of Statistics; Regression and Correlated Data; Intermediate Microeconomics; Intermediate Macroeconomics; Introduction to Statistical Computing; Applied Statistics; Public Economics; Statistics Designing Experiments; Communication for Statisticians.

SKILLS

Teamwork/Leadership	Critical Thinking	R	Microsoft Excel
Project Management	Technical Documentation	Python	SQL/MySQL/PostGreSQL
Analytics and Reporting	Problem Solving	Power BI	Business Process Design
Tableau	Microsoft Azure Fundamentals	Microsoft SQL Server	Azure Data Studio
Github	HTML/Web development	Statistical Analysis	Data Analysis/Analytics

WORK Experience

Accenture Consulting Development Analyst

Minneapolis, MN August 2021 - November 2022

Senior Analyst

November 2022 - Present

Project Experiences

Data Scientist

August 2023 – Present

Leveraging Python and Excel to conduct data cleaning and clustering of survey data in CSV files to be later used for data visualization and acquiring insights.

Data Quality Analyst

July 2022 – July 2023

- Constructed SQL queries which were used to create and update reports for audits that were later used by the Microsoft automation flows. These flows automatically sent emails to follow up with client project managers for data cleaning purposes in order to improve the data quality and the data integrity of the data sources.
- Created SQL queries, data validations and utilizing Excel tools such as Pivot Tables to create new reports for data analysis and reporting and generated reports and metrics for stakeholders. Some of these queries were fed into Power-BI and Tableau Dashboards to provide the client with the desired metrics and data coming from a variety of different project management tools.
- Assisted in creating a Tableau dashboard to conduct data cleaning efforts during the March 2023 fiscal month in order to help the company save costs and allow them to use their monthly budget for allocation and optimization.
- Created Excel reports using SQL in order to run monthly audits with the purpose of conducting data cleaning efforts for 100+ projects before the month's fiscal date and ensure the client maximized capitalization of over \$50 million dollars in costs. This involved taking care of missing names and determining how the project was financed and using Excel X-Lookups to further check for additional fields in other data sources not found in SQL server databases.

Business Analyst

- Conducted data analysis on the Visit types using Excel to analyze and determine the highest occurrences of a patient's reasons of visit per center during the 2019 to 2022 period. Used the analysis to create visuals that illustrated the centers with a high visit volume that were to be prioritized for the CRM scheduling framework.
- Conducted blocks data analysis using Excel to analyze the highest number of block usage when the patient gets scheduled for a visit. Used the data analysis to create visuals and a report that illustrated the highest number of block usage and recommended to the team to remove blocks that were least used from 2021 and onwards.
- Supported the clinical scripting workflow through the creation of clinical scripts and data analysis on keyword mapping. Conducted the keyword mapping data analysis using Excel to match symptoms with similar or different naming to ensure that they are accounted in the CRM scheduling framework.

Data Analyst

September 2021 - December 2021

- Assisted in creating an underlying data process to streamline and automate data from various sources to support reporting and dashboards and constructed data tables and views within the ETL development environment in the Microsoft SQL server database for SSI package development and the data migration process.
- Created design documents, data tables and structures in the ETL development process and test scripts and assisted in the data cleaning and data organization from the ETL development stage to the data migration stage.
- Loaded the data into the server for clean-up, end-to-end testing and migration to support dashboard building, reporting, and wireframe completion.

US Bank Saint Paul, MN

Global Securities Specialist

- June 2020 August 2021 Worked with clients and administrators in creating and managing global accounts for trade.
- Analyzed and rectified invalid trade instructions in the market via SWIFT and inbound SWIFTS (electronically sent trades). Made recommendations with other global teams to best meet the client and their business needs.
- Worked on internal projects for the specific team and at the global custody level.
- Assisted in the MUFG conversion for advanced markets such as South Korea and Brazil.